Finding Aid for the Russell Birdwell Papers LSC.0114
UCLA Library Special Collections
Russell Birdwell papers
1915-1951
1936-1946
UCLA Library Special Collections
Birdwell, Russell
LSC.0114
29.51 Linear Feet (59 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Russell Juarez Birdwell was a reporter for Hearst Newspapers and subsequently the head of publicity for David O. Selznick (ca. 1936-193), for whom he directed the publicity campaign for Gone with the Wind. Thereafter he worked independently as publicity agent for actors and other celebrities and for American businesses. The collection pertains both to individual clients and to Birdwell's personal and professional interests, and includes extensive correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, and press releases.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Unknown.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942303813606533
Biography
Russell Juarez Birdwell was born on October 17, 1903. He worked for Hearst newspapers in Los Angeles and New York, and covered Charles Lindbergh's takeoff for Paris. He directed two silent movies in 1929 and a short in 1933. Subsequently he became the head of publicity for David O. Selznick. In February 1939 he opened his own office, Russell Birdwell and Associates, in Beverly Hills and New York, with occasional offices in London and Chicago. Among the many he publicized were actresses Carole Lombard, Marlene Dietrich, Janet Gaynor, Joan Blondell, and Jane Russell; companies Celotex and Associated Filmmakers; businessman Howard Hughes; King Carol II of Romania; and major films including Gone with the Wind and The Outlaw. In 1939 he published the autobiographical novel I Ring Doorbells. In 1941 he traveled to England and wrote the book Women in Battle Dress (1942) based on his observations. In later years he published a volume of poetry (1969) and the novel Mount Horeb (1972). He died on December 15, 1977 in Oxnard, California.
Scope and Content
These papers date almost entirely from the years 1936-1946. In this period Birdwell was employed by David O. Selznick (1936-1939) and operated his own publicity agency (1939-1946). Items include extensive correspondence and memoranda, newspaper and magazine clippings, press releases, and photographs. Materials pertain to both Birdwell's clients and to his personal and professional interests.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Client files.
Correspondence.
Personal.
Photographs.
Office.
Miscellaneous.
Motion picture industry -- Public relations.; Press agents -- United States -- Archives.; Birdwell, Russell--Archives.
- 1. Client files
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains papers pertaining to Birdwell's clients and the movies, radio shows and other things that he publicized. Types of documents include correspondence and internal memoranda, newspaper and magazine clippings, and press releases.
  - 1.1 Persons and Companies
    Contains items pertaining to specific clients.
    - Adrian, Gilbert, ca. 1942 February-March (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ankers, Evelyn, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Associated Filmmakers, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Belmont Radio Corporation, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Berini, Mario--Clippings, ca. 1944 September-December (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Berini, Mario--Clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Berini, Mario--Concert programs, ca. 1944 October-1945 January (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Berini, Mario--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944 October-1945 May (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Berini, Mario--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944 July-1945 May (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Berini, Mario--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Berini, Mario--Miscellaneous, ca. 1944 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Berini, Mario--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Berini, Mario--Press releases and brochures, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Bickford, Charles--Clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Bickford, Charles--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Boots, Colonel N. Jay, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Boots, Colonel N. Jay--Brochures, ca. 1944 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Boots, Colonel N. Jay--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Boots, Colonel N. Jay--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Boots, Colonel N. Jay--Miscellaneous, ca. 1944 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Borge, Victor, ca. 1945 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Brown, Joe E., ca. 1944 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Joe E.--Correspondence, ca. 1944 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Brown, Joe E.--Press releases, ca. 1944 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Carey, Harry, ca. 1944 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Carey, Harry--correspondence, ca. 1944 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Carey, Harry--Press releases and clippings, ca. 1944 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Carlisle, Kitty--Clippings, ca. 1945 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Clippings, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Clippings, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Clippings, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Clippings, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Clippings, interview notes, and press releases, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Correspondence, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Correspondence, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Correspondence, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Interview notes, 1943 October 21 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Miscellaneous, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Newspaper clippings, ca. 1943 September-1944 January (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Newspaper clippings, ca. 1943 November (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Newspaper clippings, ca. 1943 November (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Newspaper clippings, ca. 1943 November-December (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Press releases, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Press releases, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Carol, King of Romania--Press releases and clippings, ca. 1943-1944 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Celotex--Clippings, ca. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Celotex--Clippings and brochures, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Celotex--Clippings, brochures, and miscellaneous, ca. 1943 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Celotex--Clippings, press releases, and miscellaneous, ca. 1943 February-August (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 November-1943 May (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Celotex--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Celotex--Dahlberg, Mrs. Bror--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Celotex--Dahlberg, Mrs. Bror--Press releases and clippings, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Celotex--Draft newspaper layout, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Celotex--Miscellaneous, ca. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Celotex--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Celotex--Press releases and speeches, ca. 1943 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Celotex--Press releases, speeches, and notes, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Celotex--Press releases, speeches, and notes, ca. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Celotex--Rough proofs of Washington dormitory mat page, ca. 1943 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Celotex--Site plan, east section, Calvert houses, and photographs, ca. 1943 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Celotex--Smith, Carleton, ca. 1943 June (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Celotex--Smith, Carleton, ca. 1943 June-August (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Celotex--Smith, Carleton, ca. 1943 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Celotex--Willis wedding, 1943 July-August (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Chaplin, Charles, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith, ca. 1942 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Clippings, 1942 August, November (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Clippings, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Clippings and Correspondence, 1942 November (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence, 1942 July 11, 1942 September 3 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Notes and press releases, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases, ca. 1943 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases, ca. 1942 November-December (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Collins, Ted, and Kate Smith--Press releases and biographical material, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Craig, James--Correspondence, 1942 July 28 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Craig, James--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Craig, James--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Craig, James--Winchell's Guest Column, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Day, Laraine, ca. 1942 October-December (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Dietrich, Marlene, ca. 1936-1943 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Includes correspondence handwritten by Dietrich.
    - Donaldson, Ted, ca. 1944 December-1945 June (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Dorlan--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, 1944 October-November (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Dorothy, Miss (Dorothy Garland)--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Dorothy, Miss (Dorothy Garland--Clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Drew, Ellen--Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, and clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Esme of Paris--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1945 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Fairbanks, Douglas Jr.--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      Includes Fairbanks autograph.
    - Foch, Nina--Clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Foch, Nina--Correspondence, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Foch, Nina--Press releases, biography, notes, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Fowler, Gene, ca. 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Frazier, Brenda, ca. 1939 May (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Gable, Clark--Clippings, ca. 1938 December (Box 27, Folder 7)
      See also Lombard, Carole.
    - Gaynor, Janet, ca. 1937-1939 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      Includes Gaynor autographs.
    - Gaynor, Janet--Contract with J. Walter Thompson Company, 1939 June 16 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Goddard, Paulette, ca. 1937-1940 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Goulding, Edmund, ca. 1939 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Goulding, Edmund, ca. 1939-1940 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Harrigan, Nedda--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Harrigan, Nedda--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Harrigan, Nedda--Press releases, biography, notes, ca. 1942 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Howard, Mary--Clippings, ca. 1945 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Howard, Mary--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Howard, Mary--Press releases, biography, and miscellaneous, ca. 1945 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Hudson, Rochelle, ca. 1944 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Hughes, Howard--Clippings, ca. 1940-1942 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, Howard--Correspondence, memoranda, and miscellaneous, ca. 1940-1942 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Hughes, Howard--Interviews about, ca. 1941 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, Howard--Kaiser joint venture, ca. 1942 August-October (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, Howard--Kaiser joint venture--Clippings, ca. 1942 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Hughes, Howard--Kaiser joint venture--Clippings, ca. 1942 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Hughes, Howard--Kaiser joint venture--Clippings, ca. 1942 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Hughes, Howard--Kaiser joint venture--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Hughes, Howard--Preston Sturges partnership, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Keating, Larry--Biography, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Kolker, Henry--Press Releases, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Kosleck, Martin--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Kosleck, Martin--Press releases and biography, 1942-1943 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Kramer, Maria--Correspondence and clippings, 1946 May (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - L'Anglais, Paul, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Lawton, Fleetwood, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Lawton, Fleetwood--Clippings and memorandum, ca. 1944 October-1945 January (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Lederer, Francis--Clippings, 1944 January-February (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Lederer, Francis--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1944 February-March (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Lippincott, J. Gordon, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Lippincott, J. Gordon--Correspondence, memoranda, clippings, and press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Lombard, Carol, ca. 1937-1942 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Lombard, Carole, and Clark Gable--Clippings, 1938 November-December (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Love, Inc., ca. 1938 November-1939 April (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Lynch, Teddy (Mrs. J. Paul Getty)--Correspondence, 1944 October (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Manning, Irene--Clippings, 1944 November, 1945 April (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Margo--Clippings, ca. 1942 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Margo--Correspondence, memoranda, and press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Mayer, Louis B., ca. 1938-1939 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Monti, Mili, ca. 1944 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Moray, Helga--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Moray, Helga--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1944 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Moray, Helga--Press releases and clippings, ca. 1942-1943 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Moray, Helga--Press releases and other publicity, ca. 1942 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Music Corporation of America, 1939 January-February (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Navarre, Joana, ca. 1942 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - North, Sterling--Clippings, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - North, Sterling--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - North, Sterling--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - North, Sterling--Notes, ca. 1945 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      Includes interview notes.
    - North, Sterling--Press releases, ca. 1945 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Novis, Donald--Biography, press releases, correspondence, and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Novis, Donald--Clippings, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Novis, Donald--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Novis, Donald--Press releases and biographical notes, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Parks, Larry, ca. 1945 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Pearce, Al, 1941 July-August (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Perry, Nora, ca. 1940 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Pommer, Erich--Biographical material, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Pommer, Erich--Press release, ca. 1940 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Pommer, Erich--Press releases, ca. 1940-1941 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Clipping, 1945 August 31 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Kostelanetz original tour diary, 1944 December-1945 March (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Letters from first overseas tour, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Miscellaneous, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Includes drafts of speeches.
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Miscellaneous, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      See also Correspondence and Press releases.
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Pons, Lily, and Andre Kostelanetz--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Powell, Dick, and Joan Blondell--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Powell, Dick, and Joan Blondell--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Powell, Dick, and Joan Blondell--Press releases, ca. 1940 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Ray, Rene--Correspondence, memoranda, and notes, ca. 1942 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Ray, Rene--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Reynolds, Helene, ca. 1942 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Rhonie, Aline--Biography, 1941 March 21 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Russell, Jane, ca. 1942 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      See also The Outlaw.
    - Scott, Martha--Clippings, ca. 1945 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Scott, Martha--Clippings, 1942 August 25 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Scott, Martha--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942-1944 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Scott, Martha--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Scott, Martha--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Scott, Martha--Press releases and speech, ca. 1942-1944 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Scott, Martha--Speech and press releases, ca. 1942-1945 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Shaw, Artie--Correspondence, press releases, and clippings, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Sidney, Sylvia, ca. 1944 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Simms, Ginny, ca. 1944 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Simms, Ginny--Press releases and other publicity, ca. 1944 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Starrett, Charles, ca. 1942 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Starrett, Charles--Press releases, correspondence, and clippings, ca. 1942 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Stevens, K. T. --Biography, press releases, and clippings, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Stevens, K. T. --Biography, press releases, and clippings, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Stevens, K. T.--Clippings, radio script, and press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Stevens, K. T.--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Stewart, Larry, ca. 1945 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Stone, Michael, ca. 1944 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Stone, Michael--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1940-1944 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Stone, Michael--Press releases and clippings, ca. 1940-1944 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Stromberg, Hunt, ca. 1942 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Stromberg, Hunt, ca. 1942 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Tailored Woman, Inc., ca. 1946 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Tailored Woman, Inc.--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1946 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Tennyson, Jean, ca. 1946 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Terry, Don, ca. 1946 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Tilton, Martha, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Tilton, Martha--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Tilton, Martha--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Tilton, Martha--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tilton, Martha--Press releases, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Tuchock, Wanda, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Tuchock, Wanda--Press releases, ca. 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - United Teachers of New York City, ca. 1946 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Verdugo, Elena, ca. 1944 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Verdugo, Elena, ca. 1944 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Whelan, Arleen--Biography and notes, ca. 19451 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Whelan, Arleen--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 March-November (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Whelan, Arleen--Press releases, ca. 1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Wicker, Ireene--Biography and press releases, ca. 1945 April-1946 January (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Wicker, Ireene--Clippings, 1945 June-July (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Wicker, Ireene--Clippings, ca. 1945 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Wicker, Ireene--Correspondence, 1945 June-August (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Wicker, Ireene--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1945 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Wicker, Ireene--Press releases, notes, and biographical material, ca. 1945 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Woodworth, Marjorie, ca. 1942 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Woodworth, Marjorie, ca. 1942 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Young, Loretta--Clippings, 1939 April 17, 1942 July 11 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Young, Loretta--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Young, Loretta--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Young, Loretta--Correspondence and memoranda, ca. 1942 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Young, Loretta--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Young, Loretta--Press releases, ca. 1942 (Box 23, Folder 10)